# ■ sahamer[at]ncsu[dot]com ¶ Sivana Hamer ♠ sivanahamer

# Sivana Hamer

Computer Science Ph.D. Student at North Carolina State University interested in empirical software engineering research to help software development and developers. I work in the Realsearch and WSPR research groups, advised by Dr. Laurie Williams. I am currently researching software supply chain security.

### **EDUCATION**

PhD. Student Computer Science	2023-pres.
Advisor: Dr. Laurie Williams	_
Universidad de Costa Rica	sé, Costa Rica
M.Sc. Computer Science and Informatics	2023
Thesis: Mining software repositories to automatically measure developer code contribution	ns.
Advisor: Dr. Christian Quesada-López	
Grade: 9.93/10. Graduation with honors.	
B.S. Computer Science and Informatics	2020
Grade: 9.72/10. Graduation with honors.	
EXPERIENCE	
Universidad de Costa Rica	2020 - 2023 and Database
Carnegie Mellon University	United States
Research internship as student visitor - Software and Societal Systems Department	jan - mar 2022
With: Dr. Bogdan Vasilescu	
Universidad de Costa Rica	sé, Costa Rica 2019 - 2023
Research projects: "Automated procedure for measuring contributions from repositories of velopment projects". (Project No. 834-C1-011). Research instructor. "Empirical evaluation ology for the automation of the measurement of software functional size". (Project No. Research instructor, graduate research assistant and undergraduate research assistant.	n of a method-
Universidad de Costa Rica	2018 - 2019
(CI-0126), and Probability and statistics (CI-0115).	

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

Software engineering, software security, software supply chain, empirical methods, mining software repositories, software measurement, software assessment, and value-based software engineering.

#### AWARDS

- Goodnight Doctoral Fellowship.
- North Carolina State University Provost's Doctoral Fellowship.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- [P9] Hamer, Sivana, Marcelo d'Amorim, and Laurie Williams. Exploring students' behaviors and perceptions in continuous measurement of software projects. In *Deep Learning Security and Privacy Workshop*. IEEE Security and Privacy Workshops (SPW), 2024
- [P8] Christian Quesada-López, Hamer, Sivana, and Marcelo Jenkins. Exploring students' behaviors and perceptions in continuous measurement of software projects. In *Latin American Computing* Conference (CLEI). IEEE, 2024
- [P7] Erik Kuhlmann, Hamer, Sivana, and Christian Quesada-López. Visualización de software como ciudad: Un análisis de percepciones y experiencias de estudiantes. In Latin American Computing Conference (CLEI). IEEE, 2023
- [P6] Hamer, Sivana, Christian Quesada-López, and Marcelo Jenkins. Students' perceptions of integrating a contribution measurement tool in software engineering projects. In IEEE International Conference on Software Engineering Education and Training, 2023
- [P5] **Hamer, Sivana**, Christian Quesada-López, and Marcelo Jenkins. Automatically recovering students' missing trace links between commits and user stories. In *Conferencia Iberoamericana de Software Engineering (CIbSE)*, 2021
- [P4] Hamer, Sivana, Christian Quesada-López, and Marcelo Jenkins. Students projects' source code changes impact on software quality through static analysis. In Quality of Information and Communications Technology, pages 553–564. Springer International Publishing, 2021
- [P3] Hamer, Sivana, Christian Quesada-López, Alexandra Martinez, and Marcelo Jenkins. Using git metrics to measure students' and teams' code contributions in software development projects. CLEI Electronic Journal, 2021
- [P2] Hamer, Sivana, Christian Quesada-López, Alexandra Martínez, and Marcelo Jenkins. Measuring Students' Source Code Quality in Software Development Projects Through Commit-Impact Analysis. In *International Conference on Information Technology & Systems*, pages 100–109. Springer International Publishing, 2021
- [P1] Hamer, Sivana, Christian Quesada-López, Alexandra Martínez, and Marcelo Jenkins. Measuring students' contributions in software development projects using Git metrics. In 2020 XLVI Latin American Computing Conference (CLEI). IEEE, 2020

#### LANGUAGES

• Native or bilingual: English and spanish.

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

- Programming languages and other technologies: Python, Java, R, LATEX, C#, C++, C, HTML, CSS, UML, JavaScript, Bash, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, and Neo4j.
- Frameworks and libraries: ASP.NET, Flask, NUnit, JUnit, Selenium, Bootstrap, jQuery, React, and Unity.
- Software tools: Git, Bamboo, Jenkins, JIRA, Microsoft Visual Studio, and Visual Studio Code.